Hello, my name is Clan. I am a health
insurance advisor and I am from Thrissur.   As
usual, today is
a comparison day for health insurance policies
.  So, if you are looking for good health insurance,
try to watch this video in its entirety without skipping.
Before getting into the video, I'll share a little experience I had two days
ago and then
get into the video.  It's nothing more than
a customer who called me after watching a video on YouTube and asked, "
Sir, I need to get insurance
."  I've been
studying about that insurance for about six months.  I haven't been able to
pick it up yet.
Reason had said that he tried to take the initiative, but he was unable to do so financially as he had said.  So
he bought some of my quotes, saying that I should get health insurance today anyway
.  So, when he finally finished speaking,
he said that two
days ago, he had shown his mother a small
variation on EasyJil.  So
I need to take out this policy so I can go
see the doctor tomorrow.  So, if he thinks that's his
idea,
he believes that if he takes out this policy and shows it to the police, he can claim it.
I told him,
sir, that you should
take insurance anyway. I suggested to
him that if nothing else,
tomorrow when he goes to see the doctor, he will go with
this report that there was a variation in the PCG.
Anyway, when he goes to the doctor, the
doctor will mention it in the
report.
Or he will say that it came today. The
doctor will write a report anyway.
Then this report will
go to the insurance company. When the insurance company
goes, they will
ask for the first consultation paper. This may lead to
a situation where our claim is not received. So, the
reason I am saying this here is that after all, there will be many of us who
think like this. There may be those who
think that it is not enough to take a policy after getting sick. Of
course, we will not be able to take a policy.
So,
instead of making excessive comparisons, it would be better to take a policy
there and then do
a comparison as I said.
Now, naturally, you know.  When
taking a policy, the rate is very
high. If so,
we can take it as an EMI,
we can take it as a loan. We can also
take insurance in a way that we can pay off in small installments.
So, insurance is not only that, if we want to
take an insurance and we don't like their
service,
what should we do if we don't like the service of the company? When the next renewal time
comes, we can
port it to that company and if we want to port it to another company, we can do it by keeping
our seniority.
But if we get sick, we
can't change. So, what can I
say?
Health insurance is so flexible. So, if
we have a
desire in mind, try to take it as soon as possible. We know
when and what kind of issues will come to us. We don't have any problems. So, be
careful and
try to take it. And in the same way, there have
been some updates in insurance. As I said, especially
in the case of senior citizens, now
we know that the premium of senior citizens seems to be
very high at the renewal time.
The company had been increasing it in many places,
but it had put a cap on it, saying that
annual
premiums should not be increased by more than 10 percent. As a
prelude to that, it had cut
a commission for our insurance agency, including senior citizen premiums
.  Well,
that's a great thing.  And in the
same way,
after looking at all the policies that are currently being released,
we are now moving on to a comparison
video.  So, as you
can see in this video, all these
products are designed in a way that increases the annual premium
.  In other words,
we used to say that we
had a slab system and that the premium would change only after five years
.  But as
mentioned above,
insurance companies
design their products in a way that increases premiums annually.   For no other reason, when
I
spoke recently, I understood that
after five years or 10 years, we can now see many policies. Five
x 10
x means that after five years, a
person who took 10 lakhs out of 50 lakhs will have a coverage of 50 lakhs
or after 10 years, it will become one crore.
So the company's base
policy is still only 10 lakhs, but this amount
has been collected as a bonus. So
what is the risk that insurance companies face? It is a
big risk. That is why they
increase the premium like this. So let's
go to the video. Today,
we will take the
products of three companies for comparison. One is a
plan called Tatage Medical Select. It has been launched for me for one,
two or three days.
Then there is
a plan called HDC Ragod Optima Secure. It is the
best plan for NRICs
because they are giving a discount of 40%.
HDC Ragod Optima
Secure and then Manipal.  Cigna's so-
called Sara Uttam series is very much about two
things. First, the rates are very
low. And
as for Manipal, LIC is now planning to acquire a 49
percent stake in Manipal Cigna
.
I think
sometimes people enter LIC health insurance through
Manipal Sys
.  So,
today we will be comparing products from three companies
.  So, the
first
parameter we're going to take is the room train
.  If we
look at Tata's policy now, and
look at Medical Select, we are
offered a single private room.
But I have brought a rider as an option with this so that I can
choose a room
.  If you add us,
we can choose a room
.  If HDC
is coming to Optima, if Optima is coming to Secure, then
I am in the room.  It is an enabled option.
And similarly, if you
come to Manipal, as mentioned earlier, single
private rooms are offered.  But
we have brought a rider to this.
So, after we get that rider, we can
choose a room.  Always
try to choose the best room.
Because sometimes, if there is a situation where
no rooms are available at the hospital we go to, as they say,
we may have to choose the room they say.  So, I
always
try to choose the policies that govern room selection.  And in the same way, now
ICU day care, organ donor expenses, AYUSH
treatment, all these are covered by all insurances,
up to some sub-limit, and
full expenses are covered
.  So I'll
take it back and say it again.  And
similarly, pre- and post-
hospitalization, that is, the expenses
before hospital admission and the expenses after discharge, can be
claimed. If we
look at this in insurance, if we
look at Tata's policy, we can claim the expenses
before 90 days and the
bills of 9 days after discharge. If we
go to Regula, we can submit the bills of 60 days in Optima Secure and the
bills of 180 days after discharge. If we go to
Manipal Signal,
we can claim the bills of 90 days and the bills of 150 days after discharge.
And similarly, the restoration feature, if we say
restoration,
these are the basic features. If we say
then even if we have a policy of 10 lakhs, even after
using these lakhs, we will get
another 10 lakhs.  Restoration is
a feature that is restored unlimitedly. Recently, a
trainer at Tata said that an
example was that we are
going to a big hotel, and when we are drinking water, the
waiter comes and
refills it again. It is the same in
health insurance. That is, if
we have already made a claim and it is
10 lakhs, then that
10 lakhs is there again. It is not
possible. It is always full.
So that is what
this restoration
means. Restoration is available to us in all three companies. If you
select Tata's Medicare, you can
bring it as a rider.
After adding a rider, we can
use the restoration unlimitedly. That is, after 10 lakhs, if
another member of the family comes in for something, we
can use it again. Similarly, if you
look at Optima Secure, it has
unlimited in it.
They have also brought this as a rider, similarly
Manipal has also brought it in Cigna.
As a rider, we mean this rider, which is
an optional cover. Once added,
we
can use it for unlimited restoration. Similarly,
health checkup is a health checkup.
We should
note that it is not a test prescribed by a doctor and
done. Health
checkup is meant as a
preventive health checkup.
Insurance companies say that we get a package in our IP
labs.
IP CBC profile or
a 2500 package like that.
So, package-like tests are what we mean
here. If you
look at Tata,
their tier is cashless. Once you go to the network,
we can do it cashless. It only
comes as a network. If it is in HDS,
we can buy it through reimbursement.
Now, for someone who has a policy of 10 lakhs,
We can claim
for health check-up up to 5000. We can
do it through reborment. We can go to our nearest
lab and
submit the claim if we want. If it is in Manipass, we have to go to the
tie network.
After submitting the claim according to our choice, we will not get it, but
we will get the health check-up only if we go to the network they say.
So, these are all the basic
features that come with it, but beyond this, there are
many
unique features that
can be seen in this policy. We will
discuss more about those unique
features. These are some of the
features that I found unique. The first
feature that comes in this is bone coverage.
This coverage feature was first
introduced in ICC Alavet.
One of the special features of this is that once we have set it, no matter
how much expense we incur in our lifetime,
we can
use it as soon as we claim it.
That is, now
I am
taking a policy of 10 lakhs and I am going to need treatment expenses of 50
lakhs or 1 crore rupees.
So, in that first claim, the full amount of
expenses that came in, that is the total that we can claim, we can get it once.
Then, that same
feature that is given in IC Salvate, the same
feature that is given in Tata's Medicare
Select is also given. The name of
that feature is called Infinite Advantage.
That is, a policy of 10 lakhs.
I am going to need treatment expenses of 50 lakhs
or 1 crore rupees tomorrow.
So, in the first claim
itself, we can
use it once for life. A feature that
we have added a rider and put it in.
Then, in the same way, they have brought an air li and a rider in
this coverage.
That is, the special feature of this is that if we pay the
premium for three years in two years, if we pay it
together, then we get 10  If
we take a policy of 1 lakh for two years,
we can use 20 lakh rupees in the first
claim itself. If we
calculate the premium amount for three years first, then if we have a policy of 10 lakh rupees,
we
can use 1 lakh rupees in the first claim itself. So, this is
a feature that comes in the coverage.
Tata and similarly
HDS have also brought a similar feature.
A feature called limit list means that we have an
infinity sum insured. No matter how much
treatment expenses we have,
we can claim it once after taking the rider as mentioned above.
In this, if we take a policy of 50 lakhs or
above,
we can claim it twice in our lifetime.
Then there is a benefit called secure benefit in it,
that is, it is a policy of 10 lakhs,
but I can
use the coverage of 20 lakhs in the beginning. Even if it is a
policy of 50 lakhs, we can claim it in the beginning.  It also
offers a feature that can be used in the claim itself, up to Rs. 1 crore. It is
called Secure Benefit. But
unlike all of this,
Manipal has introduced a rider called Itila Oru Anant, which is meant for those who want to work out in the arena
.  If we talk about the special features of this Anant, there are
four Asu conditions that they mention.  One is
heart-related conditions,
cancer, stroke, as well as organ or
bone marrow transplant. If
any of these four diseases occur, we
can use them early one time, no matter how much expense we incur. If the remaining two policies we saw are once in a
lifetime,
Manipal Signal says that early one time can be
used for these four diseases. In other policies,
we have any illness, which is also mentioned here. For
four
diseases, the same as
seen in HDS, they also give
surplus benefit and
they have brought a rider, that is, 2X
coverage
from day one, if it is 10 in the first claim itself, then a
claim of 20 lakhs can be
used in the first claim itself.
These are riders, you just have to
add them according to your needs.
Similarly,
a feature that I have noticed is that in the case of bonus, if we
look at the case of bonus, now if we want bonus, if we want
bonus, if we renew the
policy of 10 lakhs, we
renew it.  If you go, insurance
companies will say something extra
benefit or something, the bonus is a feature that gives
our sum insured. So if you
look at this, now the
inbuilt one is 100%. If we
add a rider and take it,
now if it is a policy of 10 lakhs,
it will become 20 lakhs. If we do not
add a rider as a rider option,
it
is an inbuilt feature in Tata and it increases by 100%.
Or as we
said, we are also given an option,
a 1% discount.
What do we say? If we say that we do not want that amortizing
bonus, we can
take a 1% discount or
choose any one of them. We have
brought a rider special with it. If we
say that it is a super charge bonus and take a rider,
then the above
mentioned features will be gone.
We will not get the discount, but if we consider
this as a benefit, this
super charge  After taking the bonus benefit,
our 10 lakh policy will
become a five-fold coverage for us, which will increase fivefold in five years. There
is such an advantage. This is
a feature that is now available in many insurance companies. It is a non-
respective claim, meaning that whether a claim
comes or not, we will get this
cumulative bonus, that is,
10 will
become 50 lakhs after five years. That is what it
means. Similarly, if we
look at HDS, 100%
is the cumulative bonus and it is inbuilt. It
increases by 50 percent annually.
This is called plus benefit. In HDS, this is also called Manipal
Signal, although it says that the maximum is 100 percent and it
increases by 50 percent annually. But here too, they
have brought a rider called Gulak Benefit,
which means that we add this benefit.
Once done, the company provides us with 10X coverage,
meaning that by the end of 10 years, our
cover will have
increased 10 times.
That's Gulak, it's a rider, it
's an optional rider.  But
I think what
I have seen in many companies that have come out now is that now in
Care Health's Ultimate and
Star Health's Super
Star, they are giving infinity cumulated
bonus,
that is, if it is 10 now, then 20, 30, 40, 50,
and so on, every year it goes up by 100%. There is
no limit there.
Here, the limit is specified and it is
specified as 10X or 5X.
Similarly, many people ask whether
these non-medical items can be
covered in our insurance.
Non-medical items
are some of the items that are listed, like this cotton swab syringe. Well, those are not included in this.
We have to add them as riders. We are
asking as an option whether to add them or
not. If we look at the start,
we have NA rider, a
rider that covers non-medical expenses.  Once we do that,
we will get the items in this list covered. Similarly, if it is in
HDC, it is called the inbuilt protected benefit. So if
we have added the rider, it is the inbuilt that
comes as an inbuilt rider, not the inbuilt
rider. So after we have added it, I think HDC also covers the full expenses of these non-medical items. They cover the same as the expenses of large food. Similarly, if you look at Manipal Signal, they have brought the rider called NM N, which means it is a rider to cover non-medical items.
Only if we add it,
we will get the non-medical items
covered. Similarly,
maternity
coverage is also covered in all these policies. Maternity
coverage is a little more internal.
Now, if maternity is in Tata,
they
have brought it as a rider. They have said that the rider is maternity care.  What we are
getting is that after we add that, the
waiting period is two years. If
we want,
we can optionally add a rider for maternity and reduce it to one year.
Then 10 percent of this is the
maximum coverage for the other things they say. In this, the new bone is also added. This means that if I
take a policy of 10 lakhs,
I get one lakh as the maximum. In this, the
new bone is also
covered within that amount. When
I just
compared the premium, if a person is 35 or 30 years
old and has a 10 lakh line, if we
look at this two-year maternity wait period, we get
₹34,810.  If we
reduce this to one year, it
comes to ₹46,698.  If we
reduce it to one year, the premium for those in the
30-35 age category per ₹10 lakh
.  This
was recently introduced in HDFS as well, in Rider Optima
Secure.
They might bring a rider just because they say it's parenthood
.  So, once we have added that rider, as
mentioned above,
we have a two-year
wait period here.  It
is 24 months.  There is an option in this
.  If we want, there is
a variant saying 50,000, 1 lakh, 1 lakh, 2 lakh
.  So we can
choose from it as we wish.   If we choose
Appam, we
will have to pay extra for the meal. If
we take one lakh, we will have to pay 38,000 rupees, and if we
take a lakh, we will have to pay 9,000 rupees
.  So, no matter
what age you take it for, you just need to add this
premium to that base
premium
.  Now, if we look at it roughly, if
we plan in such a way that we can get maternity coverage of Rs 1 lakh at the age of 35 or 30, the premium is Rs 53,000. The
premium is Rs 53,747.
Similarly,
Manipal Signal Maternity Coverage is also being offered.
they have brought a newborn baby expense rider.
After taking the rider add-on, we can use this benefit,
which is 20 percent. We take
20% of the sum policy and
take a policy of Rs 10 lakh and
get a maximum of Rs 500,000. In this, we get newborn expenses and
delivery expenses covered. It is important to note that the waiting period is
months, which
cannot be reduced to one year or two years. The waiting period is 36 months. If we
look at the premium, the other one is now one
year, and if we look at the first year premium, it
comes to Rs 3,362.  If
we plan in a way that allows us to get coverage, all
three of them
come with coverage as mentioned above. There
are other plans in the market that are better than this. I think if you have a plan like
Aspire, it covers newborn baby
coverage up to two months
.  So, if a newborn baby is
a little more important, Aspire
is a good choice.  The same is true for the
waiting period for pre-existing diseases
.  This is really what
we often need to pay attention to when buying insurance
.  Because if we
have any issues, we should mention them and
try to get the policy taken out.  If something has
come and gone, we
should try to pick it up by saying so.  In any
normal insurance policy, the
policy becomes active only after three days have passed.
But this
does not apply to accident cases.  Then there is a list of some illnesses that are specified as a 24-month specified
illness
.  Now, when it comes to slow growth,
we only start
getting coverage after 24 months for kidney stones, varicose veins, and cataracts
.  So this is the category
list.  Dad,
we only get that particular illness after 24 months
.  Then, in the
same way, if you look at the 36-month waiting
period, it is
36 months for pre-existing diseases. If
I have any current diseases, then I will
get them only after 36 months. If you think that you should be covered tomorrow after taking the policy, you will never be able to
walk. Then, in this, there is an
advanced care rider and it has been introduced. If you think that what does
this mean in Tata,
then ABCD, asthma,
BP, cholesterol, diabetes, and similar diseases are covered after the days of advanced care. If you are in such a difficult situation, try to take the policy forcibly. Similarly, even if you are in HD, now this chronic care rider has been introduced. After 30 days, ABCD diseases are covered. Asthma, BP, cholesterol,
diabetes, etc., you should add this rider. If you are
experiencing such difficulties, try to
take chronic care forcibly.
Similarly, Manipal  Even though it
is a signal, they have introduced a rider called Saradhi.
After 30 days, it covers diseases like ABCD.
It also covers obesity as an extra. If you are
facing such difficulties after 30 days, then
definitely try to add these raids and get the policy
.  Likewise,
its premium is something we are all waiting for
.  If we
look at the premium of Medicare Select, the premium for
coverage worth Rs 10 lakh at the age of 35-30 is
around 1134. If we
look at the premium for a person aged 65-60, it is
around 4743. No riders have been added
because it becomes a good product only after adding riders
.  I think
they've brought a lot of riders into this
.  I
have about 18 optional riders.
So try to choose it according to your needs
.  And
similarly, when we search, we can
see OPD, Dental,
IVision, Eye Care, etc. and we can
see it here.  But
we
don't get it as reimbursement like we do with Medicare Premier.   You
can only use this OPD benefit if you go to the network.  As far as I
know, it is only
coming as a network in our Kerala.
It's happened all over the North.  But as they
say here, there is no reimbursement for medical expenses,
OPD or
dental expenses, etc.,
as they say.  So
pay attention to that.  Similarly, if you
go to HDC Optima Secure, the comparative rate is
higher. For HDC
products, the
premium for a person aged 35-30 is Rs 22,359 per 10 lakh. If it goes to
65-60, the premium
is Rs 80. The premium is a little
higher. But one thing to note is that if you
take 10 lakhs, there
is an effect of Rs 20 lakh because the secure benefit is
inbuilt in it. Pay
attention to that. Then if you come to Manipal's Sarva
Uttam series, the
premium is very low. As mentioned, it comes at Rs 975. If you add
riders, if you
go to 65-60, the premium
comes at Rs 3,260. If we add riders, if we
look at it further, there are a lot of riders. There are also 12
riders, according to our
needs.
Try to choose. I think the premium
comparability is very low in Manipal
Sigon's Sarvottam series. But it is important to note that the
premium is increasing annually here.
Similarly, if you
look at the discount on Tata's Medicare Select, you will be
given a 7% discount, which is called a professional discount.  So, if anyone with PF and Easy wants to,
we
can apply for this.
Similarly,
if you look at HDC Optima Secure, they are offering a discount of around 40%. For
those with NRI status, or those with a passport and a PC,
we have an NRI
discount available and will
get a discount of around 40 percent.  Not only that, but if we
set a deductible,
we
can significantly reduce our premiums.
Deductible means that an expense up to Rs. 5,000 is taken from my account.
Then Manipal Singhi does not give any
special discount for it.
Then, as usual, when you
take it every three years, we are
given about 10 percent for all insurance. Now, try to take the premium for two years
together according to your
financial situation. Of course,
I have tried to share a lot of information in this in a way that is possible. So, if you
still have some doubts in your mind,
my WhatsApp
number is given below. You can
send a message to it
or you can call it and
ask. If you
are just taking a policy, then thank you. Greetings
dear. If you like the videos of mustard seeds, you should also join.